<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Than&#39;s Trans-America Cycling Tour Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Than&#39;s Trans-America Cycling Tour Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 25: Higginsville MO to Watkins Mill State Park in Lawson MO</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/15_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/15_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Super challenging ride today, 3000+ elevation gain, 68 miles, a substantial chunk with majo headwinds. Not a lot of beautiful scenery or wildlife, just basically a ride to get from point A to point B.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We crossed over the Missouri again, that was a crazy section &amp;ndash; very strong crosswind with major gusts, so all of us were trying very hard to stay onm the shoulder and not get too close to the (small) guardrail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 24: Boonville MO to Higginsville MO</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/14_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/14_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back to riding on pavement! Super zoomy ride today, we had a huge tailwind, which was lovely &amp;ndash; getting wafted along as if you were riding an e-bike or something. The route itself was nice too, very slow rolling hills and lots of wide open spaces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Selfie on the road:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/15ZWLw4hzDWqqhEVlcds1cBpYckYHZA7a/preview&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The road in the background is pretty representative of what we had to work with today &amp;ndash; surface ok, but with a nasty loose gravel shoulder, you definitely want to stay off that unless it is an absolute emergency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 24: Tebbetts MO to Boonville MO</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/13_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/13_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One last ride on the Katy trail, around 63 miles this time. Good weather! A bit on the warm side, but the first few hours were cool at least. Good riding, lots of folks riding in spite of the fact that it was a Tuesday morning. We have reached a total of 1263 miles as of the end of this day, so coming up on one third finished in a few days. We are also coming up on our next zero day this weekend, everyone looking forward to that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 23: Augusta MO to Tebbetts MO</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/12_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/12_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice long ride (70ish miles) all on the Katy trail today, it was a good one. Light rain during the morning, almost too light for rain gear, so nothing serious. I rode a bit with Simona, a bit with the pack, a bit with Mike, and for a good chunk of the ride I was on my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Snack with Chet, Tom, and Deb at the Holzhauers Cafe in Portland MO.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 22: Alton IL to Augusta MO</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/11b_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/11b_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice ride today, route distance was 53 miles, but at the end of the day I rode a bit over 60. Very flat, not much in the way of hills. Today was also the first day back (from injury) for our rider Theo &amp;ndash; we looked great out on the bike, it was good to see him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://ridewithgps.com/embeds?type=trip&amp;amp;id=281627580&amp;amp;sampleGraph=true&#34; style=&#34;width: 1px; min-width: 100%; height: 700px; border: none;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had a couple of long stops, one for coffee in Saint Charles, then another stop in the town of Defiance, where there was a nice (and extremely crowded) brew pub.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 22: Reflection on Gear at around the One Thousand Mile Mark</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/11a_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/11a_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short post to reflect on biking gear and such for this trip so far:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the top of the list is my bike, which has been absolutely rock solid, super happy with it so far. No mechanical issues, it has ridden well, the tires have performed superbly, the various bags have adequate space. Gold star on that front. I was nervous when I started the trip since virtually everyone else on the tour is riding a road bike (mostly Trek Domane&amp;rsquo;s) but my gravel bike with the big tires is doing me just fine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 21: Vandalia IL to Alton IL</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/10_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/10_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a final push through Illinois, riding all the way up to the town of Alton (a St Louis suburb) on the banks of the Mississippi. This was about a 75 mile ride, split halfway between SR40/SR140 and a set of smaller roads and bike trails towards the end of the ride. Again we had great riding conditions, sunny, favorable breezes. Today I rode with the Chet, Mel, Tom and Terrence &amp;ndash; they were striking a moderate and not blistering pace (yay).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 20: Casey IL to Vandalia IL</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/09_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/09_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots more riding on SR 40, so we had to ride with care again and watch the traffic carefully.  Good riding conditions though, no headwinds, sunny, weather really quite nice altogether. I rode with Mike for the most part, so pretty zippy speeds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Teutopolis IL we spotted a bunch of tents set up outside the Teutopolis Savings Bank, and discovered that they (the TSB employees) were having a charity cookout. We contributed some cash and sat down to have a burger, which was nice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 19: Cloverdale IN to Casey IL</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/08_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/08_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long ride today, 72 miles with 2500 feet of elevation gain, but way less punishing than our last long ride &amp;ndash; the winds were favorable and the roads were good. The first 30 miles in particular were very zoomy and pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At mile 35 we stopped in Terre Haute Indiana, home of ISU; my fellow rider Mike and I had a nice second breakfast at a diner in town.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A big chunk of the riding today was on SR 40, a two-lane highway with a very limited shoulder, so we had to ride carefully and keep a close eye on traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 18: Franklin IN to Cloverdale IN</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/07_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/07_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shorter day today, 55 miles, which I think was a big relief to everyone, we were all still worn out this morning after yesterday&amp;rsquo;s super-challenging ride. Today&amp;rsquo;s ride was also mostly on nice back roads, and the winds were well-behaved, so it was a pleasure all around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I rode with Mel and Chet today, and spent a fair amount of time in the &amp;ldquo;pack&amp;rdquo;, not trying to push the pace (much needed after yesterday).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 17: Liberty IN to Franklin IN</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/06_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/06_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Started raining steadily this morning around 5am, so we had our first &amp;ldquo;pack up and go&amp;rdquo; in the rain for the trip (we&amp;rsquo;ve had lots of other rainy episodes, but for some reason not in the morning). I am getting good now at managing dry-bags and garbage bags to keep the wet stuff separate from the dry in my luggage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was really a beast of a ride today, no question. 71 miles, 2241 elevation, plenty of up and down. First 20 miles in the rain (bit cold too), all geared up, then at some point it cleared and we started peeling off layers. Second 50 miles was into a serious headwind, really brutal in parts. We were also on a busy road (state route 44) for a couple of long sections, including one where there was a not only a tiny shoulder but with rumble strips, and lots of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 16: Waynesville OH to Liberty IN</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/05_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/05_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My cooking experience last night with Chet was successful but kind of messy and chaotic &amp;ndash; it started to rain hard partway through the meal prep so we had to kind of dance around in the mud to get it all done.  There were various other mishaps as well but the final product was quite tasty &amp;ndash; we made &lt;a href=&#34;https://cooking.nytimes.com/recipes/1025342-one-pot-chicken-meatballs-with-greens&#34;&gt;one-pot chicken meatballs with greens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep last night in Caesar Creek State Park, very quiet. Lots of dew and condensation inside the tent in the morning tho.  Cool weather to start, 48 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 15: Mount Sterling OH to Waynesville OH</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/04_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/04_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The weather forecast when we looked at it last night was grim &amp;ndash; all of us were steeling ourselves for a &amp;ldquo;rain all day&amp;rdquo; ride, but lo and behold in the morning we had cloudy skies but no precipation, huzzah! We had quick breakfast and headed out (with all our raingear packed along just in case).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Short ride, 52 miles, mostly flat, no headwinds, just a tiny bit of rain &amp;hellip; it was great, walk in the park.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 14: Zero Mileage Day in Deer Creek Lake Park, Mount Sterling OH</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/03_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/03_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zero day in Mount Sterling Ohio. Very soggy morning for me (tent had beaucoup water in it last night), so I did my best to get things dried out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weather forecast: rain all day, so a mixed bag &amp;ndash; on the one hand we did&amp;rsquo;t have to ride through the miserable weather, but on the other hand we will have rain for our relaxation day. The group opted to get in the van and drive in to Columbus to explore en masse, I think nobody wanted to sit around in a wet tent all day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 13: Buckeye Lake to Deer Creek Lake in Mount Sterling Ohio</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/02_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/02_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slightly soggy start for this ride, but we managed to get organized and on the road at the appointed hour. So far my tent has been handling to wet weather ok. I rode with the gang for an hour or so, then picked up the pace and rode with Mike into Lancaster OH, and then on into Circlevill, a nice medium-sized city where the van was stopped at  Kroer for food shopping.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 12: Senecaville Ohio to Buckeye Lakes Ohio</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/01_may_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/01_may_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lovelty sunrise this morning, and it was a good night sleeping, so something to be thankful for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s ride was a tough one: 69 miles with 4600 ft elevation gain. I rode with the pack for the first half or so of the ride, we stopped for lunch in the tiny town of Chandlersville. Lo and behold a local boy scout troop had built a little covered pavilion with picnic tables, perfect spot for a break. Across the street was a small and crusty-looking antique nicknack shop; Deb went in to ask if she could use their bathroom, and when she came out she was holding cold bottles of water for all of us (super nice guy there just gave them to us). Shopping in Zanesville at the Riesbeck market (large and well stocked).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 11: Wheeling West Virginia to Senecaville Ohio</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/30_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/30_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Super lovely weather for cycling this morning &amp;ndash; around 49 or 50 at the start, cool breezes, sunshine.We started our ride with a trip across an old suspension ridge to take us over the river and into Ohio. First 10 miles or the ride were a bit twisty and turny but we eventually made our way to some nice country roads and traveled west. Total of 60 miles, today, but real hills this time (3800 feet of elevation gain). Some of the climbs were steep, we had to really work in spots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 10: Pittburgh PA to Wheeling WV</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/29_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/29_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our group was all definitely ready to ride this morning, rest day done with, everyone was packed and ready to hit the road well before schedule. Warm (60) at the start, and sunny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ride getting out of Pittsburgh was a bit dicey, we had a very sketchy left turn to get off Carson Ave across a busy highway that was pretty nerve wracking, but we all stuck together in a pack and made it through.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 9: Zero day in Pittburgh</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/28_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/28_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rest day here in Pittsburgh PA. It is good to not be under the gun to pack up stuff&amp;hellip; just roll out of bed and move on to whatever is on your agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great weather here! Enjoying the sunshine. Also, the hotel/hostel that the ACA booked for us, Traveler&amp;rsquo;s Rest, is still amazing &amp;ndash; just a really cool place to stay, highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent the morning helping Theo (our rider from the Netherlands) wrangle with the people at the cell phone store to get a US cell plan, that was quite the electronic adventure.  I had done a little research ahead of time to make sure his phone was compatible, but there was still a lot of drama and complication. The person behind the counter needed lots of nudging and arm-twisting (I think what they really wanted was for him to buy a new phone, but that was not going to happen).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 8: GAP trail ride from West Newton PA to Pittsburgh PA</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/27_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/27_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cold start today, high 30&amp;rsquo;s, but it was decided that we would have a late (1 hour delayed) start since we only had 35ish miles to ride.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://ridewithgps.com/embeds?type=trip&amp;amp;id=275522991&amp;amp;sampleGraph=true&#34; style=&#34;width: 1px; min-width: 100%; height: 700px; border: none;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was an easy ride, cool, a bit of a headwind, but another enjoyable day out in the sunshine (was better than what we had to deal with the previous day). I rode mostly with Mel; we chatted about our kids and places we&amp;rsquo;d visited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 7: GAP trail ride from Confluence to West Newton PA</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/26_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/26_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was steady rain during the night, continuing through breakfast so we all hustled to get our gear and tents packed up wet, always a tricky business. Thankfully it was not a super cold rain, probably about 60 degrees. We hit the road around 8 and got onto the trail. Very muddy business!  Shoes and bikes all very liberally coated after a couple of hours. Slight downhill ride following the river; we cycled poast Ohiopyle (cute little town, very big with white water kayak/raft folks) and then eventually Connelsville (bit less interesting).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 6: GAP trail ride from Cumberland MD to Confluence PA</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/25_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/25_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, the Cumberland YMCA turns out to be not such a great place to camp after all, at least not for me. Turns out that there is an active freight train line about 100 meters to the south, and there is also a highway about 500 yards uphill on a ridge. Big and very noisy trains were coming through ever couple of hours overnight, and on the highway there were trucks using their air brakes descending into town. Not a great night&amp;rsquo;s sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 5: Third and final day on C&amp;O Canal Towpath, to Cumberland MD</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/24_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/24_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One last day on the C&amp;amp;O Canal Towpath trail.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After all of the chaos and mayhem caused by downed trees from the previous ride, our leaders decided that it would be a good idea to bypass the first few miles of the trail, just to get well and truly away from the tornado damage. So we piled all of the bikes on top of the van, packed all the riders into the inside, and set off to drive to a spot that looked good. With all the packing and organizing this took a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 4: Second day on C&amp;O Canal Towpath, to Hancock MD</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/23_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/23_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long cycling day today, 77 miles &amp;ndash; on gravel no less (eek).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our guides got up early and had our breakfast ready a bit earlier than the normal 7am, that was good. We headed out on our way.  Today I rode a bit with Deb, we chatted about various things and enjoyed the scenery, then eventually I detached and headed on my own for a good stretch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lots of time to observe the Potomac, which is quite a river.  I have seldom seen a river of that size that has so many rocky bits in it &amp;ndash; it seemed as though every time I looked over at it there were collections of rocks sticking just out of the river, with plenty more below to make trouble for boats (I guess the rockiness is probably one of the big reasons they put in the canal).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: First day on C&amp;O Canal Towpath, to Brunswick MD</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/22_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/22_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our first real riding day, woohoo! Much excitement for getting started with the real stuff. Of course to get to the real stuff we had to cycle from the Crystal City part of DC up to the start of the towpath which is not far from the Watergate complex.  That was actually more work than I had thought it would be, the small group I was in got lost (trying to follow signs for a detour) but eventually got back on track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Shakedown Ride in DC</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/21_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/21_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Made it to DC and joined up with the tour group. It is a genial crew &amp;ndash; I enjoyed meeting everyone and beginning the process of getting to know them. We have two guides/leaders &amp;ndash; Simona and Dennis, I am sure they are going to be fun to tour with as well. This morning we grabbed our bikes and headed out on a &amp;ldquo;shakedown&amp;rdquo; ride to make sure everyone&amp;rsquo;s equipment is working properly, etc.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to the ride:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trusty bike ... or not?</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/18_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/18_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another training ride yesterday; it was a bit cold and windy but I did a good solid ride (63 miles) to try to prime the pump for my upcoming tour.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At mile 61 or thereabouts, however, I started to hear an odd clunking noise coming from my front derailleur, and when I looked down I saw that one of my front chainrings (the smaller one) had almost completely come off &amp;ndash; of the four bolts holding it on, only one was still there. Eeek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A first posting on my trans-am blog</title>
      <link>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/15_april_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.wanderingsquid.org/blog/posts/15_april_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all, welcome to the blog I&amp;rsquo;m keeping to document the Trans-America bike ride I&amp;rsquo;m doing this summer. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve created a lot of content using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blogger.com/&#34;&gt;Blogger/Blogspot&lt;/a&gt;, I decided this time around to &amp;ldquo;roll my own&amp;rdquo; so as to have a bit more control (you can click on the &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo; link above for more of the grubby details).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A photo of my trusty bike:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1jJrArLVhnGpVSTUgu6jqAlPfBw9TKDoa/preview&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.salsacycles.com/products/2022-cutthroat-c-grx-810-2x&#34;&gt;Salsa Cutthroat&lt;/a&gt;, a bike in theory designed for long-distance gravel rides (in particular the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tourdivide.org/&#34;&gt;Tour Divide&lt;/a&gt; route).  Carbon fiber frame to keep the weight down, but in other respects a high level of sturdiness for dealing with rough roads and such.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
